From con man to congressman
The Distinguished Gentleman is a comedy film directed by Jonathan Lynn.
A Florida con man uses the recent death of the long time Congressman from his district, who he just
happens to share a last name with, to get elected to his version of paradise, the U.S.
Congress, where the money flows from lobbyists.
Thomas Jefferson Johnson, played by Eddie Murphy.
Dick Dodge, played by Lane Smith.
Miss Loretta, played by Sheryl Lee Ralph.
Olaf Andersen, played by Joe Don Baker.
Celia Kirby, played by Victoria Rowell.
Arthur Reinhardt, played by Grant Shaud.
The Distinguished Gentleman is a 1992 American
political comedy film starring Eddie Murphy.
The film was directed by Jonathan Lynn.
In addition to Murphy, the film stars Lane Smith, Sheryl Lee Ralph, Joe Don
Baker, Victoria Rowell, Grant Shaud, Kevin McCarthy, and Charles S.
The film's plot is centered on politics, specifically what members of
Congress and lobbyists do to get what they want in Washington, D.C.
The film explores themes of businessman, greed,
falling in love, bribery, political comedy.
The tone is lighthearted.